New York’s Eleven Madison Park has become the first vegan restaurant to be awarded three Michelin stars.
纽约的麦迪逊公园11号成为首家荣获米其林三星的纯素餐厅。
The fine dining establishment received its first three-star Michelin rating in 2011 when the menu was famed for its fancy animal-based dishes.
这家高级餐厅于2011年首次获得米其林三星评级，当时其菜单以精致的荤菜著称。
However, last year, the restaurant’s co-owner and famous chef, Daniel Humm, made the bold decision to remove meat from the menu, citing our unsustainable food system.
然而去年，餐厅联合老板兼知名主厨丹尼尔·胡姆以现有食物体系不可持续为由，大胆决定把肉类撤下菜单。
While cow milk is still served for tea and coffee, the menu is almost 100 percent vegan.
虽然喝茶和咖啡时仍提供牛奶，但菜单几乎百分之百是纯素的。
At the time, Humm acknowledged the move was risky, admitting that “it wasn’t clear if guests would come”, but called the gamble “a risk worth taking.”
当时，胡姆承认此举有风险，坦言“不清楚客人会不会来”，但称这次冒险是“值得一冒的风险”。
“In view of the climate crisis, I didn’t want to open the same restaurant,” Humm told the Financial Times in an interview.
“鉴于气候危机，我不想再开一家和以前一样的餐厅，”胡姆在接受《金融时报》采访时说。
“If we can show the possibilities of eating plant-based food in this setting, it can open a lot of doors” for others to follow.
“如果我们能在高级餐厅这样的环境中展示植物性饮食的种种可能，就能打开许多扇门”，让其他人随后跟进。
Now, this impressive new accomplishment validates Eleven Madison Park’s decision to take meat off the menu and embrace plant-based foods, with Michelin’s 2022 New York guide branding it “a bold vision of luxury dining”.
如今，这项令人瞩目的新成就证明，麦迪逊公园11号把肉类撤下菜单、欣然接纳植物性食物的决定是正确的；米其林2022年纽约指南称之为“奢华餐饮的大胆构想”。
“We took the leap to transform Eleven Madison Park into a plant-based fine dining restaurant knowing in our hearts this was what we believed in,” stated Humm on Instagram.
“我们勇敢地迈出一步，把麦迪逊公园11号转变为一家植物性高级餐厅，我们打心底里清楚，这正是我们所信奉的，”胡姆在Instagram上写道。
“Last night, we were honored to be awarded three Michelin stars for the 11th year in a row.
“昨晚，我们连续第11年获得米其林三星，深感荣幸。
I am so grateful to the team members who contributed through its nearly 25-year history.
我非常感激近25年来为餐厅贡献过力量的团队成员。
We are also grateful to our guests and partners who believed in our vision and encouraged us to push harder.”
我们也感谢相信我们的愿景、鼓励我们更加努力的客人和合作伙伴。”
Three Michelin stars is the highest award, given to chefs who are at the peak of their profession.
米其林三星是最高荣誉，授予处于职业巅峰的厨师。
“Their cooking is elevated to an art form and some of their dishes are destined to become classics,” reads Michelin’s website, in a clear nod to plant-based foods’ growing significance in the culinary world.
“他们的烹饪升华为一种艺术形式，其中一些菜肴注定会成为经典，”米其林网站上写道，这显然是在肯定植物性食物在烹饪界日益重要的地位。
“I think luxury companies have a real role to play and a responsibility,” says Humm.
“我认为高端奢华企业确实可以发挥作用，也负有责任，”胡姆说。
“The more creative we are, the more beautiful and delicious our future will be.”
“我们越有创造力，未来就会越美好、越美味。”